<resources>
    <string name="app_name">BiogasHome</string>

    <!-- TODO: Remove or change this placeholder text -->
    <string name="hello_blank_fragment">Hello blank fragment</string>
    <string name="biogas_explnations">Biogas is a type of biofuel that is naturally
        produced from the decomposition of organic waste.\nWhen organic
        matter, such as food scraps and animal waste, break down in an anaerobic
        environment (an environment absent of oxygen) they release a
        blend of gases, primarily methane and carbon dioxide.\nBecause this
        decomposition happens in an anaerobic environment, the process of
        producing biogas is also known as anaerobic digestion.\nAnaerobic digestion
        is a natural form of waste-to-energy that uses the process
        of fermentation to breakdown organic matter.\nAnimal manure, food scraps,
        waste water, and sewage are all examples of organic matter that can produce
        biogas by anaerobic digestion.\n\nDue to the high content of methane in biogas
        (typically 50-75%) biogas is flammable, and therefore produces a deep blue
        flame, and can be used as an energy source.\n\nBiogas is the mixture of gases
        produced by the breakdown of organic matter in the absence of oxygen (anaerobically),
        primarily consisting of methane and carbondioxide.\nBiogas can be produced from
        raw materials such as agricultural waste,manure, municipal waste, plant material,
        sewage, green waste or food waste.\nMethane is a versatile, sustainable gas that can
        be used to perform everyday tasks like heating water and cooking food with surprising
        simplicity.Unfortunately producing it and using it at home may seem messy, but below we have a
        simple DIY instruction on making a biogas digester.\nAll grazing animals have bacteria that are
        needed for creating methane in their guts,
        with cows being the most efficient creators of the gas.\nIf you
        can’t get hold of cow manure on a regular basis, there are other options
        as horse or sheep manure can function effectively too.Another advantage of this is
        that careful creation and management of the biogas
        digester allows for stacking functions.\nOnce a biodigester is built for
        the creation of methane, the semi-liquid substance left behind is a great fertilizer.\n
        Creating a basic bio digester does not have to be an expensive endeavour.Only a few items
        are needed, and the concepts behind creating one are simple.
</string>
    <string name="raw_materialstxt"> Before considering the materials required, it is worth noting that
        the gas produced won’t be pure methane.\nCow manure yields about 60% methane while the rest is carbon
        dioxide with a touch of hydrogen sulfide.\nThere are ways of extracting that, but it is a far more advanced
        design that requires biogas scrubbing. But as a beginner, it’s best to try an Easy Do-It-Yourself(DIY) biogas
        digester. The following are the most basic materials for this process:\n
        ● Two drums – One drum must be slightly
        smaller than the other so that the smaller one can be fitted into the larger one.\n
        ● Manure suited to creating
        the needed anaerobic bacteria culture.\n
        ● Input pipe and funnel for pouring in processed food waste.\n
        ● Output pipe for draining waste for fertilizer.\n
        ● 3 uniseals.\n
        ● Valve for controlling gas out flow.\n
        ● Pipe for connecting outflow valve to burner Gas Burner\n
        ● Chicken wire &amp; cable ties to make a cage for the biodigester.\n
        ● For cold climates and winter – black spray paint (if drums aren’t black)
        and/ or aluminum tape or other outdoor insulation materials.
        \n\nRaw Materials suitable for biogas production include but not limited to the following:\n-Manure
        is needed to start the process and maintain this particular method of producing
        methane.\nHowever, only using manure is not the most effective method of continuously
        producing methane.\n-Adding chopped up plant materials that grazing animals naturally
        turn into methane such as grass produces a great yield.\n-Leaves and rotting vegetables
        are also options for feeding a biogas digester and creating methane, once the system has
        been established.\n-Biodegradable waste from enterprises and industrial facilities, such as
        surplus lactose from the production of lactose-free dairy products\n-Spoiled food from shops\n
        -Biowaste generated by consumers\n-Bludge from wastewater treatment plants\n-Manure and field biomass
        from agriculture\n\n</string>
    <string name="safety_b1">When manure is anaerobically digested, the biogas produced is primarily
        composed of methane and carbon dioxide, with lesser amounts of hydrogen sulfide, ammonia, and
        gases. Each of these gases has safety issues. Overall, biogas risks include explosion, asphyxiation,
        disease, and hydrogen sulfide poisoning.\nExtreme caution is necessary when working with biogas.
        Adequate ventilation, appropriate precautions, good work practices, engineering controls, and adequate
        personal protective equipment will minimize the dangers associated with biogas.\nWherever possible,
        digester-associated tasks and maintenance should be performed without anyone having to enter confined
        spaces, including pits.\nSystems should be initially designed so that confined space entry is not required
        to perform maintenance.</string>
    <string name="safety_b2txt">Methane, approximately 60% of biogas, forms explosive mixtures in air.
        If biogas is diluted between 10% and 30% with air, there is an explosion hazard.\nFor instance, in 2003, several
        explosions on Canadian swine farms were thought to have been caused by the methane in biogas exploding
        (Choinière, 2004). Hydrogen sulfide and ammonia are also potentially explosive.\nBecause of the explosion
        hazards, no open flames should ever be used near a digester.\nAlso, equipment such as large engines and electric
        generators must be suitable to the environment so a spark will not ignite the gas.\nExplosion-proof equipment
        and electrical service, as well as non-sparking tools, should be used around digesters and biogas.\nThere MUST
        be no smoking near the digester or related biogas lines and equipment.</string>
    <string name="safety_b3">Asphyxiation is a process or state of being deprived of oxygen.\nAsphyxiation from biogas is a concern in an enclosed space where manure is stored.\n
        Osbern and Crapo (1981) report one case of three people who died from asphyxiation created by swine manure
        gas in an enclosed space. Even open-topped manure pits can generate methane at a sufficient rate to push out
        the air above the manure and render the space oxygen-deficient.\n Never enter a facility where manure is stored
        or where there is a suspected biogas leak as natural ventilation cannot be trusted to dilute the explosion
        hazard sufficiently.\nAiring out a facility does not impart safety, as some of the gases produced are heavier
        than air.\nIf a person is found unconscious in such a facility, do not enter the facility because you may be
        overcome as well.\nContact emergency services so that firefighters wearing self-contained breathing apparatus
        (SCBA) can safely retrieve the victim.</string>
    <string name="safety_b4">Animal manure contains bacteria, viruses and, possibly, parasites.\nBiogas is generated by
        the anaerobic digestion of manure, which occurs because of the bacteria present in animal wastes, some of which
        can produce infection.\nWhen handling waste material, exercise appropriate precautions by using personal protective
        equipment to avoid contact with manure. Washing after working around the digester is recommended.\nIt is
        particularly recommended to wash hands before eating and drinking and before touching the eyes or other mucous
        membranes.\nKeeping the digester facility clean will reduce disease hazards as well as the spread of odors and
        fly populations in the digester facility.</string>
    <string name="safety_b5_1">Always contact the designer or expert who assisted in setting up the plant,
        in case you are not the one. Failure to heed manufacturer warnings may result in death or serious
        injury. Contact the manufacturer for maintenance and service requirements and availability of service.</string>
    <string name="safety_b5_2">A safety walk-through can help you determine potential hazards and preventative
        measures. Cornell University developed a comprehensive self-assessment guideline for farmers. It is
        intended to be used by farm owners and managers or farm staff who are responsible for the operations
        and/or maintenance of anaerobic digesters and their related processes. It provides guidance for process
        and job evaluation with suggestions based on typical potential hazards for farm digester systems and their
        associated preventative measures.</string>
    <string name="safety_b5_3">Explosion, suffocation, and poisonous gas hazards may be detected using gas sensors.
        These sensors include both disposable and electronic sensors. Electronic sensors need testing regularly,
        and these sensors may have a disposable component that needs periodic replacement. Only qualified people
        should use these sensors to determine if an area is safe.\n\n</string>
    <string name="ben_b1">Biogas is a renewable, as well as a clean, source of energy.\nGas generated through
        biodigestion is non-polluting; it actually reduces greenhouse emissions (i.e. reduces the greenhouse
        effect).\n\nNo combustion takes place in the process, meaning there is zero emission of greenhouse gasses
        to the atmosphere; therefore, using gas from waste as a form of energy is actually a great way to combat
        global warming. Unsurprisingly, concern for the environment is a major reason why the use of biogas has
        become more widespread.\n\nBiogas plants significantly curb the greenhouse effect: the plants lower methane
        emissions by capturing this harmful gas and using it as fuel.\n\nBiogas generation helps cut reliance on the
        use of fossil fuels, such as oil and coal. Another biogas advantage is that, unlike other types of renewable
        energies, the process is natural, not requiring energy for the generation process.\nIn addition, the raw materials
        used in the production of biogas are renewable, as trees and crops will continue to grow.\n\nManure, food scraps,
        and crop residue are raw materials that will always be available, which makes it a highly sustainable option.</string>
    <string name="steps_body">\n**Step 1**\nEnsure that the drums fit tightly enough to prevent oxygen getting in and methane
        escaping, but not too snug so that the smaller drum doesn’t slide.
        \nThe smaller drum should still slide down on it’s own due to its own weight so that there here is pressure from the smaller drum on the gas that is 
        created.
        \n\n**Step 2**\n
        Three holes need to be cut into the two drums.
        \nThe solid’s input pipe and the gas outflow valve must be cut into the top of the smaller drum, while an output pipe for the leftover digested mass is
        needed at the bottom of the larger drum in order to drain the excess material for fertilizer.
        \nCut holes suited to the size of the three holes and insert the appropriately sized uniseals. It will be necessary to seal these 
        holes to ensure that gas doesn’t leak out and oxygen doesn’t get in and ruin the digestion process. As a rule 
        of thumb, your input pipe would be much larger than your outflow valve as the food going in would take up more 
        volume and the smaller space for the outflow pipe will add to the pressure needed for effectively using the bio
        gas.\n
        Make sure that they are effectively sealed by putting the drum in some water. If it seeps through and into
        the drum, it’s not well sealed and a lot of gas will be lost.
        \nLastly, the input pipe must have a sealed closure
        so that it is not left open after manure or vegetation matter has been added.
        \n\n**Step 3**\nCreate a cage for your drums
        that will prevent the top from popping off. Chicken wire shaped to give enough space for the small drum to rise 
        would do the trick. Don’t drill holes into the larger drum to secure it though. That would allow oxygen in. 
        Remember, the cage needs to allow access to the input and output pipes.
        \n\n**Step 4**\n The manure needs to be diluted
        with water at a 1:1 ratio and stirred into a slurry like consistency. Then, pour it into the bottom of the larger
        drum carefully.
        \n\n**Step 5**\n Insert smaller drum into larger drum and give the bacteria some time. After about three 
        weeks to a month, adding in some cut grass is a good way to build up the system. Don’t add too much plant matter 
        that is high in sugar such as grains, fruits and vegetables.\nFirst let the bacteria establish themselves and the 
        correct pH level with the kind of plant matter that grazing animals very effectively turn into methane. After a
        while, any leftover vegetables can be added along with cut grass. Manure is needed from time to time to maintain 
        the bacteria count.
        \n\n**Step 6**\nMaintain the temperature. If you live in a cold climate, you 
        may need to provide added insulation to your biogas digester system.\nThe temperature needed by the bacteria ranges
        between 32 and 37 degrees Celsius or about 90 to 99 degrees Fahrenheit.\nIf it drops below 15 degrees Celsius or 60
        degrees Fahrenheit the bacteria will no longer be active.\n\nA few tips for keeping the container insulated would be:
        \n● Spray paint the container black for it to attract as much heat from the sun as possible.
        \n● Bury the container in
        order for the earth to insulate the heat generated by the bacteria.
        \n● Cover the container with aluminum tape or 
        another insulation material that may be available to you that is suited to the outdoors.
        \n\n**Step 7**\n Hook up your burner to the pipe you have attached to the outflow valve and reap the
        rewards of your gas production.\n</string>
    <string name="ben_b2">Overflowing landfills don’t only spread foul smells- they also allow toxic liquids
        to drain into underground water sources.
        Consequently, yet another advantage of biogas is that biogas generation may improve water quality.
        Moreover, anaerobic digestion deactivates pathogens and parasites; thus, it’s also quite effective
        in reducing the incidence of waterborne diseases. Similarly, waste collection, and management,
        significantly improve in areas with biogas plants. This, in turn, leads to improvements in the
        environment, sanitation, and hygiene.</string>
    <string name="ben_b3">The by-product of the biogas generation process is enriched organic (digestate),
        which is a perfect supplement to, or substitute for, chemical fertilizers. The fertilizer discharge
        from the digester can accelerate plant growth and resilience to diseases, whereas commercial fertilizers
        contain chemicals that have toxic effects and can cause food poisoning, among other things.</string>
    <string name="ben_b4">The technology used to produce biogas is quite cheap. It is easy to set up and needs
        little investment when on a small scale. Small biodigesters can be used right at home, utilizing kitchen
        waste and animal manure. A household system pays for itself after a while, and the materials used for
        generation are absolutely free. The gas manifested can be used directly for cooking and generation of
        electricity. This is what allows the cost of biogas production to be relatively low. Farms can make use
        of biogas plants and waste products produced by their livestock every day. The waste products of one cow
        can provide enough energy to power a light bulb for an entire day. In large plants, biogas can also be
        compressed to achieve the quality of natural gas, and utilized to power automobiles. Building such plants
        requires relatively low capital investment, and creates green jobs. For instance, in India, 10 million jobs
        were created, mostly in rural areas, in plants and in organic waste collection.</string>
    <string name="ben_b5">Biogas generators save women and children from the daunting task of firewood collection.
        As a result, more time is left over for cooking and clean. More importantly, cooking on a gas stove, instead
        of over an open fire, prevents the family from being exposed to smoke in the kitchen. This helps prevent deadly
        respiratory diseases. Sadly, 4.3 million people a year die prematurely from illness attributable to the household
        air pollution caused by the inefficient use of solid fuels for cooking.\n\n</string>
    <string name="biogas_is_eco_friendly">Biogas is Eco-Friendly</string>
    <string name="reduces_soil_and_water_pollution">Reduces Soil and Water Pollution</string>
    <string name="organic_fertilizer">Organic Fertilizer</string>
    <string name="it_s_a_simple_and_low_cost_technology">It’s A Simple and Low-Cost Technology</string>
    <string name="healthy_cooking_alternative">Healthy Cooking Alternative</string>
    <string name="benefits_of_biogas">Benefits of Biogas</string>
    <string name="who_we_are">We are a startup Company, striving to engage majorly in solving social challenges facing  local communities.
        We seek to support, engage and work together with other teams to see to it that positive transformation is  considered essential
        and worked for.\n\nWe involve our teams by bringing in Tech concepts to aid in problem solving.\nThis is one of the major steps as to
        why you can be able to access this app and learn about setting up a Home Biogas Plant!\nWe help non-profit organisations such as learning institutions and NGOs to build learning and teaching aids transformed in form of mobile applications
        such as this.\n\n</string>
    <string name="contact_us">We would really be more than humbled to hear your views, feelings, comments or concerns.\nYou may please reach us via the following contacts:\n\nEmail:- afixus.it@gmail.com\nMobile:-  +254716002763 (Text,Call or WhatsApp)\n\n</string>
</resources>
